(Watch on www.dramacool.club Support Admin)
(شاهد على www.dramacool.club دعم الإدارة)
[Pursuit of Jade]
[السعي وراء اليشم]
[Episode 36]
[الحلقة 36]
[Three days later]
[بعد ثلاثة أيام]
[Jingque Pavilion]
جناح جينجك
So many people today.
كثير من الناس اليوم.
Quite boisterous.
صاخبة للغاية.
Yes.
نعم.
Sister,
أخت،
you can't stand being apart
لا يمكنك تحمل البقاء منفصلين
from the marquis for even one second.
من الماركيز ولو لثانية واحدة.
Why did you have to come and join the crowd?
لماذا كان عليك أن تأتي وتنضم إلى الحشد؟
He showed me support when I entered the Capital.
لقد أظهر لي الدعم عندما دخلت العاصمة.
Now that he's coming back in triumph,
والآن بعد عودته منتصراً،
of course I must be here to cheer him on.
بالطبع يجب أن أكون هنا لأشجعه.
Song Yan of the Ministry of Rites' Department of Internal Affairs
سونغ يان من إدارة الشؤون الداخلية بوزارة المراسم
was appointed to uphold ritual practice and educate the people,
تم تعيينه للحفاظ على الممارسات الشعائرية وتثقيف الناس،
yet he failed to fulfill his duties
لكنه فشل في أداء واجباته
and was derelict in his responsibilities.
وكان مهملاً في أداء مسؤولياته.
He is hereby dismissed from office
يُعزل بموجب هذا من منصبه
and sent back to his place of origin.
وأُعيد إلى موطنه الأصلي.
He shall not be trusted with an official post again.
لا ينبغي الوثوق به في منصب رسمي مرة أخرى.
Here he comes!
ها هو قادم!
[Yong'an Gate]
[بوابة يونغآن]
-Here comes the marquis! -Here he comes!
- ها هو الماركيز قادم! - ها هو قادم!
[Guo's Restaurant]
[مطعم غو]
There he is. Sister, come look!
ها هو ذا. يا أختي، تعالي انظري!
He's getting close!
إنه يقترب!
Marquis of Wu'an!
ماركيز ووآن!
♪ The world is vast ♪
♪ العالم واسع ♪
-Marquis of Wu'an!
- ماركيز ووآن!
[Yong'an Gate]
[بوابة يونغآن]
♪ The storm is rising ♪
♪ العاصفة تتصاعد ♪
♪ Day and night ♪
♪ ليلاً ونهاراً ♪
♪ We strive to save the world ♪
♪ نسعى جاهدين لإنقاذ العالم ♪
-Marquis of Wu'an!
- ماركيز ووآن!
♪ All people ♪
♪ جميع الناس ♪
♪ Are part of the past ♪
♪ جزء من الماضي ♪
Marquis of Wu'an!
ماركيز ووآن!
♪ What's the date today? ♪
♪ ما هو تاريخ اليوم؟ ♪
♪ How lamentable ♪
♪ يا للأسف ♪
Why don't you come over?
لماذا لا تأتي؟
What's there to see? I'm not going there.
ما الذي يمكن رؤيته هناك؟ لن أذهب إلى هناك.
♪ What's the date today? ♪
♪ ما هو تاريخ اليوم؟ ♪
[Yong'an Gate]
[بوابة يونغآن]
-Marquis of Wu'an!
- ماركيز ووآن!
♪ How lamentable ♪
♪ يا للأسف ♪
Eyes over here, Marquis of Wu'an!
انظر إلى هنا يا ماركيز ووآن!
Marquis of Wu'an! Marquis of Wu'an!
ماركيز ووآن! ماركيز ووآن!
-Look at me! -Please look at me, Marquis of Wu'an!
- انظر إلي! - أرجوك انظر إلي يا ماركيز ووآن!
-Marquis of Wu'an!
- ماركيز ووآن!
Look at me, Marquis of Wu'an!
انظر إليّ يا ماركيز ووآن!
[Xie]
[شيه]
Halt!
وقف!
Sister,
أخت،
why don't you throw a handkerchief too?
لماذا لا ترمي منديلًا أيضًا؟
I didn't bring any.
لم أحضر أي شيء.
Just throw one.
ألقِ واحدة فقط.
Anyone has a handkerchief?
هل لدى أحدكم منديل؟
Did you bring any?
هل أحضرت معك أي شيء؟
What's the fun in throwing handkerchiefs?
ما المتعة في رمي المناديل؟
Watch me.
شاهدني.
I'll show you what should be done.
سأريك ما يجب فعله.
I'm going to knock you out with this.
سأفاجئك بهذا.
What do you think you're doing?
ما الذي تظن نفسك فاعلاً؟
I...
أنا...
Go on and say it. What?
هيا قلها. ماذا؟
[Guo's Restaurant]
[مطعم غو]
[Xu's Restaurant]
[مطعم شو]
Who threw that hair ribbon?
من الذي ألقى شريط الشعر هذا؟
Is the Marquis of Wu'an in love with someone?
هل ماركيز ووآن مغرم بأحد؟
Hyah!
هيا!
[Marquis of Wu'an]
[ماركيز ووآن]
So many girls threw handkerchiefs along the way,
ألقت العديد من الفتيات بالمناديل على طول الطريق،
yet the marquis didn't spare a glance at them.
لكن الماركيز لم يلتفت إليهما.
Which noble family's daughter the marquis has his eye on?
من هي ابنة أي عائلة نبيلة يضع الماركيز عينه عليها؟
Isn't that the Flower-Crowned General?
أليس هذا هو الجنرال المتوج بالزهور؟
It really is General Fan!
إنه حقاً من المعجبين العامين!
Marquis of Wu'an is into her?
هل ماركيز ووآن معجب بها؟
[Jingque Pavilion]
جناح جينجك
General Fan is truly a heroine who can rival any man.
الجنرال فان هي بطلة حقيقية يمكنها منافسة أي رجل.
No wonder the Marquis of Wu'an only likes her.
لا عجب أن ماركيز ووآن لا يحب إلا هي.
So what?
وماذا في ذلك؟
The marquis is a battle-hardened warrior
الماركيز محارب متمرس في المعارك
-who won't be trapped by romantic trifles! -That's right!
- من منا لا يقع في فخّ التفاهات الرومانسية! - هذا صحيح!
That pig butcher you're fans of
ذلك الجزار الذي تعشقونه
are not worthy of the marquis at all!
إنهم لا يستحقون لقب الماركيز على الإطلاق!
Not worthy of him at all!
لا يستحقه على الإطلاق!
[Li's Wine House]
[بيت نبيذ لي]
The Flower-Crowned General is a skillful fighter.
الجنرال المتوج بالزهور مقاتل ماهر.
She captured Lord Changxin and won distinction in battle many times.
لقد أسرت اللورد تشانغشين وحققت تميزاً في المعارك مرات عديدة.
She will by no means deign to marry the marquis!
لن ترضى بأي حال من الأحوال بالزواج من الماركيز!
Stop flattering the marquis!
توقف عن تملق الماركيز!
That's right!
هذا صحيح!
The marquis, our hero, is mighty and extraordinary.
الماركيز، بطلنا، عظيمٌ واستثنائي.
He will never settle for a pig butcher like the one you admire!
لن يرضى أبداً بجزار خنازير مثل الذي تعجب به!
Right. What's so great about
صحيح. ما هو المميز في
-that lowly pig butcher? -The general contributed a lot in battle.
- ذلك الجزار الحقير؟ - لقد ساهم الجنرال كثيراً في المعركة.
She won't marry that brute you call hero!
لن تتزوج ذلك الوحشي الذي تسميه بطلاً!
What brute? Stop spewing filth!
أيها الوحش؟ كف عن التلفظ بالقذارة!
Quiet down!
اهدأ!
All we want is just a good show
كل ما نريده هو عرض جيد فقط
about a hero and a beauty.
قصة بطل وفتاة جميلة.
Can't you stop shouting and yelling?
ألا يمكنك التوقف عن الصراخ والتهديد؟
Exactly.
بالضبط.
-Look at that! -I know!
انظر إلى ذلك! - أعرف!
You're going too fast.
أنت تسير بسرعة كبيرة.
-Marquis of Wu'an!
- ماركيز ووآن!
Look here!
انظر هنا!
[Xie]
[شيه]
-Look here, Marquis of Wu'an! -Here!
- انظر هنا يا ماركيز ووآن! - هنا!
-Marquis of Wu'an!
- ماركيز ووآن!
Look at me please!
انظر إليّ من فضلك!
The heavens are unfair.
السماء ظالمة.
[Xie's Mausoleum]
[ضريح شيه]
As I am getting old,
مع تقدمي في السن،
my memory is failing too.
ذاكرتي تخونني أيضاً.
I can't believe
لا أستطيع أن أصدق
I forgot to bring your favorite osmanthus cake here today.
نسيت أن أحضر كعكة الأوسمانثوس المفضلة لديك اليوم.
You visit this place every year on this day.
تزور هذا المكان كل عام في هذا اليوم.
Do you just hate to see my parents
هل تكره رؤية والديّ؟
rest in peace
ارقد في سلام
so you come here to upset them once a year?
إذن أنت تأتي إلى هنا لإزعاجهم مرة واحدة في السنة؟
After skulking around for days,
بعد التخفي لعدة أيام،
you finally decided to show up.
لقد قررت أخيرًا الحضور.
Today is the anniversary of your mother's death.
اليوم هو ذكرى وفاة والدتك.
Let's save the fight and feud for another day.
دعونا نؤجل الشجار والخصومة إلى يوم آخر.
Anything can wait
كل شيء يمكن أن ينتظر
till the ritual to pay respects to your parents is finished.
حتى انتهاء طقوس تكريم الوالدين.
Come.
يأتي.
[Foster Family Unity and Harmony]
[وحدة وانسجام الأسر البديلة]
[Memorial Tablets for Xie's Ancestors]
[لوحات تذكارية لأجداد شيه]
You've dismissed all the Suicide Warriors.
لقد تجاهلت جميع المحاربين الانتحاريين.
Aren't you afraid
ألا تخاف؟
that I'll make you pay blood for blood, Prime Minister?
هل ستجعلني أدفع ثمناً باهظاً يا رئيس الوزراء؟
Your mother is watching right here.
والدتك تشاهدك من هنا.
Why would I put you in a tough spot
لماذا أضعك في موقف صعب؟
and disturb her peace?
وإزعاج سلامها؟
Prime Minister Wei,
رئيس الوزراء وي
today, you finally know to show care for your little sister.
اليوم، أصبحتِ أخيراً تعرفين كيف تُظهرين الاهتمام لأختك الصغيرة.
Seventeen years ago,
قبل سبعة عشر عاماً،
you returned to the Capital in the middle of deploying troops.
لقد عدت إلى العاصمة في منتصف عملية نشر القوات.
Did it ever occur to you
هل خطر ببالك ذلك؟
that my father and mother
أن والدي ووالدتي
would lose their lives for your rash decision?
هل سيفقدون حياتهم بسبب قرارك المتهور؟
Let me tell you this one more time:
دعني أخبرك بهذا مرة أخرى:
seventeen years ago,
قبل سبعة عشر عاماً،
I came back to the Capital to quell a rebellion by imperial order.
عدتُ إلى العاصمة لإخماد تمرد بأمر إمبراطوري.
Was that so?
هل كان ذلك صحيحاً؟
Then before my parents' memorial tablets, do you dare to swear
ثم أمام لوحتي والدي التذكاريتين، هل تجرؤ على الشتم؟
a solemn oath on that?
هل أقسمت يميناً رسمياً على ذلك؟
Fine. Now that we've gone this far,
حسنًا. الآن وقد وصلنا إلى هذه المرحلة،
today,
اليوم،
I might as well share a few heartfelt words with you.
ربما من الأفضل أن أشارككم بعض الكلمات الصادقة.
I raised you up
لقد رفعتك
only with the purpose of enabling you
فقط بهدف تمكينك
to shape a future for the Xie and Wei families,
لرسم مستقبل لعائلتي شي ووي،
[Foster Family Unity and Harmony]
[وحدة وانسجام الأسر البديلة]
to bring glory to our clans,
لجلب المجد لعشائرنا،
and to guard the peace of Great Yin.
ولحماية سلام يين العظيم.
That is why
لهذا السبب
I spared no effort in nurturing you.
لم أدخر جهداً في رعايتك.
Nurturing?
رعاية؟
You were simply forging a handy blade.
كنت ببساطة تصنع نصلًا عمليًا.
It just never came to your mind
لم يخطر ببالك ذلك أبداً
that this very blade
أن هذا النصل بالذات
would eventually be directed at yourself.
سيُوجَّه الأمر في النهاية إليك أنت.
And you are...
وأنت...
the one sullying the clans' reputation
الشخص الذي يشوه سمعة العشائر
and disrupting the peace of the nation.
وزعزعة استقرار البلاد.
You're acting disloyally and unfilially for being bewitched
إنك تتصرف بخيانة ونكران للذات لأنك مسحور.
by the daughter of our enemy.
من ابنة عدونا.
Who are you to talk about the greater good of family and country to me?
من أنت حتى تتحدث معي عن مصلحة العائلة والوطن؟
[Foster Family Unity and Harmony]
[وحدة وانسجام الأسر البديلة]
Today, right before your parents, I command you
اليوم، أمام والديك مباشرةً، آمرك
to make a clean break and sever all ties
لقطع العلاقات بشكل نهائي وفصل جميع الروابط
with Fan Changyu!
مع فان تشانغيو!
What gives you the right
ما الذي يمنحك الحق
to say all that to me at this very place?
أن يقول لي كل هذا في هذا المكان بالذات؟
I spent 17 years raising you.
لقد أمضيت 17 عاماً في تربيتك.
Does it not give me the right?
ألا يمنحني ذلك الحق؟
Do you...
هل أنت...
admit it
اعترف بذلك
or not?
أم لا؟
Yes, I admit it.
نعم، أعترف بذلك.
As your uncle,
بصفتي عمك،
I am to exercise the authority of your parents.
أنا مكلف بممارسة سلطة والديك.
Today,
اليوم،
I shall punish you according to the family rules.
سأعاقبك وفقاً لقواعد العائلة.
Tell him
أخبره
about the punishment!
بخصوص العقوبة!
The family rules dictate
تملي قواعد الأسرة
that anyone disloyal and unfilial
أن أي شخص غير مخلص وعاقّ لوالديه
shall receive 108 whippings.
سيتلقى 108 جلدات.
Fine.
بخير.
I will willingly take
سأقبل بكل سرور
all those whippings today.
كل تلك الضربات اليوم.
Consider it my way to return your favor.
اعتبرها طريقتي لرد الجميل.
From today on,
ابتداءً من اليوم،
stop saying disgusting words
توقف عن قول الكلمات البذيئة
like how I'm indebted to you for raising me.
مثل شعوري بالامتنان لك لتربيتي.
Do it now!
افعل ذلك الآن!
Our illustrious ancestors
أسلافنا العظماء
left a glorious name in history.
لقد ترك اسماً مجيداً في التاريخ.
All descendants are instructed
يتم توجيه جميع الأحفاد
to follow the righteous path.
اتباع الطريق القويم.
[Foster Family Unity and Harmony]
[وحدة وانسجام الأسر البديلة]
Thirty-five.
خمسة وثلاثون.
Thirty-six.
ستة وثلاثون.
Thirty-seven.
سبعة وثلاثون.
Thirty-eight.
ثمانية وثلاثون.
Thirty-nine.
تسعة وثلاثون.
Forty.
أربعون.
[Family Creed]
[عقيدة العائلة]
[Foster Family Unity and Harmony]
[وحدة وانسجام الأسر البديلة]
Ninety-nine.
تسعة وتسعون.
One hundred and four.
مئة وأربعة.
One hundred and six.
مئة وستة.
One hundred and seven.
مئة وسبعة.
One hundred and eight!
مئة وثمانية!
Yan Zheng.
يان تشنغ.
You shouldn't be here.
لا ينبغي أن تكون هنا.
I really shouldn't.
لا ينبغي لي ذلك حقاً.
But what about you?
لكن ماذا عنك؟
You knew Wei Yan was at the mausoleum.
كنت تعلم أن وي يان كان في الضريح.
why did you come here alone?
لماذا أتيت إلى هنا بمفردك؟
Why were you punished with whippings?
لماذا عوقبت بالجلد؟
General Fan, it's a breach of etiquette
يا جنرال فان، هذا خرق للآداب
for you to barge into the Xie's mausoleum.
لكي تقتحم ضريح شي.
I am not only General Fan,
أنا لست مجرد معجب عام،
but also the Marchioness.
ولكن أيضاً الماركيزة.
Why can't I be here?
لماذا لا أستطيع أن أكون هنا؟
A marriage is not valid without parental consent
لا يُعتبر الزواج صحيحاً بدون موافقة الوالدين
and a matchmaker's involvment.
وتدخل خاطبة.
On top of that,
بالإضافة إلى ذلك،
have there been proper betrothal rituals?
هل تمت مراسم الخطوبة بشكل صحيح؟
As for him marrying into your family,
أما بالنسبة لزواجه من عائلتك،
even the name he gave you is fake.
حتى الاسم الذي أعطاك إياه مزيف.
How can this marriage be taken for real?
كيف يمكن اعتبار هذا الزواج حقيقياً؟
I've had all the 108 whippings.
لقد تلقيت كل أنواع الجلد الـ 108.
You're in no position to decide for me.
أنت لست في وضع يسمح لك باتخاذ القرار نيابة عني.
A marriage certificate is just a piece of paper.
شهادة الزواج ليست سوى ورقة.
Only when I acknowledge it
فقط عندما أعترف بذلك
will it become effective.
هل سيصبح ذلك فعالاً؟
Let's go home.
هيا بنا إلى المنزل.
Not now.
ليس الآن.
Get on your knees.
اركع.
[Memorial Tablets for Xie's Ancestors]
[لوحات تذكارية لأجداد شيه]
Father, Mother, please listen.
أبي، أمي، أرجوكم استمعوا.
This lady, Fan Changyu,
هذه السيدة، فان تشانغيو،
is from Lin'an Town.
هو من بلدة لينان.
When my life was hanging by a thread,
عندما كانت حياتي معلقة بخيط رفيع،
she saved me.
لقد أنقذتني.
When I was in sheer despair,
عندما كنت في حالة يأس شديد،
she gave me her love.
لقد منحتني حبها.
During my ten-odd years on the battlefield,
خلال سنوات خدمتي العشر في ساحة المعركة،
♪ In a lifetime of storms, a fleeting bloom ♪
♪ في حياة مليئة بالعواصف، زهرة عابرة ♪
I never felt like I was truly alive.
لم أشعر قط بأنني على قيد الحياة حقاً.
♪ The most beautiful scenery becomes a poem ♪
♪ أجمل المناظر الطبيعية تتحول إلى قصيدة ♪
♪ For a chance encounter ♪
♪ للقاءٍ عابر ♪
I didn't realize
لم أكن أدرك
♪ A single letter of longing, half a lifetime apart ♪
♪ رسالة واحدة من الشوق، تفصل بينهما نصف عمر ♪
my life was worth living until I met her.
كانت حياتي تستحق العيش حتى التقيت بها.
♪ I'll burn out my passion for you ♪
سأحرق شغفي من أجلك ♪
♪ Just for a glance ♪
♪ لمحة سريعة ♪
♪ In this life ♪
♪ في هذه الحياة ♪
♪ All that I can see or hear ♪
♪ كل ما أستطيع رؤيته أو سماعه ♪
♪ Is that we'll live and die together ♪
♪ هل يعني ذلك أننا سنعيش ونموت معًا ♪
♪ On this journey ♪
♪ في هذه الرحلة ♪
♪ You're all that I care about ♪
♪ أنت كل ما يهمني ♪
♪ My soul yearns and my dreams linger ♪
♪ روحي تتوق وأحلامي تلاحقني ♪
♪ After we part ♪
♪ بعد أن نفترق ♪
♪ Where love dwells, where fear lies ♪
♪ حيث يسكن الحب، وحيث يكمن الخوف ♪
♪ Just one thought makes me sick ♪
مجرد فكرة واحدة تُشعرني بالغثيان ♪
♪ I wish to leave this world with you ♪
♪ أتمنى أن أغادر هذا العالم معك ♪
♪ We'll never be apart ♪
♪ لن نفترق أبداً ♪
I now respectfully announce to you, my departed parents,
أعلن لكم الآن بكل احترام، يا والديّ الراحلين،
that this woman
أن هذه المرأة
is the love of my life.
هو حب حياتي.
I will never betray her,
لن أخونها أبداً،
not until death do us part.
لن نفترق إلا بالموت.
♪ In this life ♪
♪ في هذه الحياة ♪
♪ All that I can see or hear ♪
♪ كل ما أستطيع رؤيته أو سماعه ♪
♪ Is that we'll live and die together ♪
♪ هل يعني ذلك أننا سنعيش ونموت معًا ♪
♪ On this journey ♪
♪ في هذه الرحلة ♪
♪ You're all that I care about ♪
♪ أنت كل ما يهمني ♪
♪ My soul yearns and my dreams linger ♪
♪ روحي تتوق وأحلامي تلاحقني ♪
♪ After we part ♪
♪ بعد أن نفترق ♪
♪ Where love dwells, where fear lies ♪
♪ حيث يسكن الحب، وحيث يكمن الخوف ♪
♪ Just one thought makes me sick ♪
مجرد فكرة واحدة تُشعرني بالغثيان ♪
I will never betray you,
لن أخونك أبداً،
♪ I wish to leave this world with you ♪
♪ أتمنى أن أغادر هذا العالم معك ♪
not until death do us part.
لن نفترق إلا بالموت.
♪ We'll never be apart ♪
♪ لن نفترق أبداً ♪
Prime Minister.
رئيس الوزراء.
Zheng!
تشنغ!
Zheng.
تشنغ.
What happened to you?
ما حدث لك؟
Why are you so badly hurt?
لماذا أنت مصاب بجروح بالغة؟
I'm fine, Aunt.
أنا بخير يا خالتي.
This is Fan Changyu,
هذا فان تشانغيو،
my wife.
زوجتي.
Aunt.
عمة.
Flower-Crowned General,
الجنرال المتوج بالزهور،
I have long heard of your formidable reputation.
لطالما سمعت عن سمعتك المرموقة.
When my life was in grave danger,
عندما كانت حياتي في خطر جسيم،
it was she who saved me.
هي التي أنقذتني.
We have pledged our lives
لقد تعهدنا بحياتنا
to each other and committed
متبادلين وملتزمين
to lifelong companionship.
إلى رفقة تدوم مدى الحياة.
Now, Changyu,
الآن، تشانغيو
take Zheng away for medical treatment.
اصطحبوا تشنغ لتلقي العلاج الطبي.
Zheng, get up.
يا تشنغ، انهض.
It is cold and damp.
الجو بارد ورطب.
What brings you here, my love?
ما الذي أتى بكِ إلى هنا يا حبيبتي؟
I noticed that you had prepared osmanthus cake but forgot to take it
لاحظت أنك أعددت كعكة الأوسمانثوس لكنك نسيت إحضارها
with you.
معك.
So I hurriedly brought it here to you.
لذلك أحضرتها إليك على عجل.
Zheng's mother loved osmanthus cake.
كانت والدة تشنغ تحب كعكة الأوسمانثوس.
In memory of her, you would
تخليداً لذكراها، ستفعل
offer it to her spirit tablet every year.
أقدمها إلى لوحتها الروحية كل عام.
This year is no exception, of course.
وهذا العام ليس استثناءً بالطبع.
Here you are.
تفضل.
What an exquisite box.
يا له من صندوق رائع!
Was it made by a master craftsman?
هل صنعه حرفي ماهر؟
I must have some more cake every day
لا بد لي من تناول المزيد من الكعك كل يوم
so the effort you put in
لذا فإن الجهد الذي تبذله
won't be wasted— your hand was hurt for making the box.
لن يضيع هباءً - لقد تأذت يدك أثناء صنع الصندوق.
Osmanthus cake is too sweet
كعكة الأوسمانثوس حلوة جداً
to be taken too much.
أن يتم تناوله بكثرة.
Got it.
فهمتها.
They make such a perfect couple.
إنهما يشكلان ثنائيًا مثاليًا.
Zheng's parents, may they rest in peace,
والدا تشنغ، رحمهما الله.
would surely be happy about it.
سيكون سعيداً بذلك بالتأكيد.
Fifteen, twenty, ten!
خمسة عشر، عشرون، عشرة!
-Fifteen, twenty, twenty! -Fifteen, twenty, ten!
-خمسة عشر، عشرون، عشرون! -خمسة عشر، عشرون، عشرة!
Drink up.
اشربوا.
What kind of stupid game is this from your hometown?
ما هذا النوع من الألعاب الغبية التي صدرت من مدينتك؟
I've been losing all night.
لقد كنت أخسر طوال الليل.
One more round.
جولة أخرى.
-Fifteen, twenty, twenty! -Fifteen, twenty, ten!
-خمسة عشر، عشرون، عشرون! -خمسة عشر، عشرون، عشرة!
Fifteen, twenty, ten!
خمسة عشر، عشرون، عشرة!
Drink up.
اشربوا.
Quick!
سريع!
Master.
يتقن.
What's the matter? Speak up.
ما الأمر؟ تكلم.
No outsiders are around.
لا يوجد غرباء في الجوار.
Here's a letter for you.
إليك رسالة.
I knew Xie Zheng wouldn't quit his quest for the truth.
كنت أعلم أن شيه تشنغ لن يتخلى عن سعيه وراء الحقيقة.
To hell with that uncle-nephew bond.
تباً لتلك الرابطة بين العم وابن أخيه.
Seems like it's time to strike.
يبدو أن الوقت قد حان للهجوم.
Come with me.
تعال معي.
What's there to do this late at night?
ما الذي يمكن فعله في هذا الوقت المتأخر من الليل؟
I have prepared a surprise for you.
لقد أعددت لك مفاجأة.
I've got you a magnificent robe and crown.
لقد أحضرت لك رداءً وتاجاً رائعين.
What do you think?
ماذا تعتقد؟
Are you out of your mind?
هل فقدت عقلك؟
This is an empress's crown.
هذا تاج إمبراطورة.
I want you to be my empress
أريدك أن تكوني إمبراطورتي
and the mother to the nation.
وأم الأمة.
You will stand by my side
ستقف بجانبي
and rule the country with me.
واحكموا البلاد معي.
So what if I become the Empress?
وماذا لو أصبحتُ الإمبراطورة؟
You're only looking for someone to share a bed with you,
أنت تبحث فقط عن شخص تشاركه السرير،
so you won't be alone when your beautiful dreams all shatter.
حتى لا تكون وحيداً عندما تتحطم أحلامك الجميلة.
What?
ماذا؟
Do you not like them?
ألا تحبهم؟
At this point,
عند هذه النقطة،
does it even matter
هل يهم ذلك أصلاً؟
whether I like them or not?
سواء أعجبتني أم لا؟
You told me not to kill,
لقد طلبت مني ألا أقتل،
so I stopped.
فتوقفت.
I have also promised you
لقد وعدتك أيضاً
not to hurt that little brat again.
ألا أؤذي ذلك الطفل المزعج مرة أخرى.
What do I have to do
ما الذي يتعين علي فعله؟
for you to willingly be my empress?
لكي تكوني إمبراطورتي طواعية؟
Kneel before me,
اركع أمامي،
and beg me.
وتوسل إليّ.
You're asking me to kneel to you?
هل تطلب مني أن أركع أمامك؟
I am the ruler of all.
أنا حاكم الكل.
What now?
ماذا الآن؟
Is that a refusal?
هل هذا رفض؟
I beg you...
أرجوك...
to be my empress.
لتكون إمبراطورتي.
I look forward to the day I become the Empress.
أتطلع إلى اليوم الذي أصبح فيه الإمبراطورة.
It won't take long.
لن يستغرق الأمر وقتاً طويلاً.
Stop messing around.
توقف عن العبث.
Give me back the Tiger Tally.
أعد لي سجل النمور.
[Xie's Mansion]
[قصر شيه]
My Lord!
يا إلهي!
My Lord.
يا سيدي.
My Lady, what happened?
سيدتي، ماذا حدث؟
Bring him to his room.
أحضره إلى غرفته.
Don't disclose a word.
لا تفصح عن كلمة واحدة.
Yes.
نعم.
My Lady, would you like to take a rest?
سيدتي، هل ترغبين في أخذ قسط من الراحة؟
I will attend to His Lordship.
سأهتم بأمر صاحب السيادة.
Let me do it.
دعني أفعل ذلك.
You may all leave now.
يمكنكم جميعاً المغادرة الآن.
Unless it is urgent,
إلا إذا كان الأمر عاجلاً،
do not disturb us.
لا تزعجنا.
Yes.
نعم.
Changyu...
تشانغيو...
After taking those 108 whippings,
بعد تلقي تلك الـ 108 جلدات،
now I can rightfully wed you
الآن يمكنني الزواج منك بشكل قانوني
following the complete marriage rituals.
اتباع طقوس الزواج كاملة.
It turns out you had already decided
اتضح أنك كنت قد قررت بالفعل
to atone for your sins this way.
للتكفير عن ذنوبك بهذه الطريقة.
Changyu,
تشانغيو،
will you let me take you...
هل تسمحين لي بأخذك...
as my wife?
كزوجتي؟
No need for that.
لا حاجة لذلك.
You have long belonged to me already.
لقد كنتِ ملكي منذ زمن طويل.
Mother Consort,
الأم القرينة،
don't...
لا...
let me die.
دعني أموت.
This is enough to last you a lifetime.
هذا يكفيك مدى الحياة.
Deliver this package safely
قم بتسليم هذه الطرد بأمان
to the General's Mansion.
إلى قصر الجنرال.
Then leave the Capital.
ثم غادر العاصمة.
Go as far away as you can.
اذهب إلى أبعد مكان تستطيع الوصول إليه.
Do not come back again.
لا تعود مرة أخرى.
My Lady, won't you leave with me?
سيدتي، ألا تذهبين معي؟
Qi Min's men have this place under close watch.
رجال تشي مين يراقبون هذا المكان عن كثب.
I cannot escape.
لا أستطيع الهروب.
Once I leave,
بمجرد أن أغادر،
more people here will die.
سيموت المزيد من الناس هنا.
Off you go.
انطلق.
Go.
يذهب.
You're awake?
هل أنت مستيقظ؟
Careful.
انتبه.
Thank you...
شكرًا لك...
for keeping me company.
لأنك كنت تؤنسني.
You took many whippings for me.
لقد تحملت الكثير من الضربات من أجلي.
How could I leave you?
كيف لي أن أتركك؟
I always thought
لطالما اعتقدت
Wei Yan hated me
وي يان كان يكرهني
because my mother took the opportunity
لأن والدتي انتهزت الفرصة
to hang herself while I was eating
أن تشنق نفسها بينما كنت أتناول الطعام
that plate of osmanthus cake out of greed.
ذلك الطبق من كعكة الأوسمانثوس بدافع الجشع.
I also hated myself for that ever since.
لقد كرهت نفسي أيضاً بسبب ذلك منذ ذلك الحين.
Later, though I conquered Jinzhou to complete my revenge
لاحقًا، قمتُ بغزو جينتشو لإتمام انتقامي.
and became the Marquis of Wu'an,
وأصبح ماركيز ووآن،
I could dream of nothing
لا أستطيع أن أحلم بأي شيء
but that revolting scent of osmanthus
لكن تلك الرائحة الكريهة للأوسمانثوس
and the hem of my mother's dress dangling under the beam.
وحافة فستان أمي تتدلى تحت العارضة.
I am still that child...
ما زلت ذلك الطفل...
who loves to cry.
من يحب البكاء.
I've never changed a bit.
لم أتغير قيد أنملة.
Now you have me.
الآن أنت تملكني.
I can protect you.
أستطيع حمايتك.
You know what?
أتعلم؟
When you left Lin'an to look for me
عندما غادرت لينان للبحث عني
and showed up covered in wounds,
وظهر مغطى بالجروح،
I thought to myself,
فكرت في نفسي،
"what's the point of vengeance?
"ما جدوى الانتقام؟"
I'm done with it."
لقد انتهيت من هذا الأمر.
I didn't want to see you cry.
لم أكن أريد أن أراكِ تبكين.
But then,
لكن بعد ذلك،
I remembered my family name "Xie,"
تذكرت اسم عائلتي "شيه"،
and that my father was Xie Linshan.
وأن والدي كان شي لينشان.
I can hardly recall his face,
لا أستطيع تذكر وجهه جيداً،
yet the barely
ومع ذلك بالكاد
stitched-up chest of his
صدره المخيط
after he was disemboweled
بعد أن تم استئصال أحشائه
and the 67 arrow-shaped wounds on his body
و67 جرحاً على شكل سهام على جسده
are still vivid in my mind.
لا تزال تلك الصور حاضرة في ذهني بوضوح.
Yan Zheng,
يان تشنغ,
I've never blamed you.
لم ألومك قط.
Wei Yan is your uncle,
وي يان هو عمك،
who raised you for more than ten years.
من قام بتربيتك لأكثر من عشر سنوات؟
You've paid him the debt of gratitude now.
لقد سددت له دين الامتنان الآن.
It is time you took revenge.
حان وقت الانتقام.
It's wrong to torture ourselves
من الخطأ أن نعذب أنفسنا
over the mistakes of others.
على حساب أخطاء الآخرين.
I got it.
حصلت عليه.
It is time.
لقد حان الوقت.
When the royal banquet is held three days later,
وعندما تُقام المأدبة الملكية بعد ثلاثة أيام،
I will enter the palace myself
سأدخل القصر بنفسي
and bring out the maids who bore witness to the truth.
وأخرجوا الخادمات اللواتي شهدن على الحقيقة.
I'll help you.
سأساعدك.
Come in.
ادخل.
Your Lordship, Your Ladyship.
صاحب السمو، صاحبة السمو.
The falcon brought back a chess record from the palace.
أحضر الصقر سجلاً للعبة الشطرنج من القصر.
Mr. Gongsun cracked it
لقد نجح السيد غونغسون في حلها
and wrote this note for Your Lordship.
وكتبت هذه الرسالة إلى سيادتكم.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
Wei Yan had an affair with a royal consort.
أقام وي يان علاقة غرامية مع إحدى المحظيات الملكية.
[Wisdom and Integrity]
[الحكمة والنزاهة]
This woman
هذه المرأة
is the love of my life.
هو حب حياتي.
I'll never betray her,
لن أخونها أبداً،
not until death do us part.
لن نفترق إلا بالموت.
To Yan, my dearest:
إلى يان، عزيزتي:
I hope this letter finds you well.
أتمنى أن تصلك هذه الرسالة وأنت بخير.
I have missed you so much since we parted.
لقد اشتقت إليك كثيراً منذ أن افترقنا.
Every time I adorn myself before the mirror,
في كل مرة أتزين فيها أمام المرآة،
put on the clothes you like,
ارتدي الملابس التي تحبها،
and watch the blooms and butterflies in the garden,
وتأمل الأزهار والفراشات في الحديقة،
I'm sad that no one is there to share my joy with.
أشعر بالحزن لعدم وجود أحد لأشاركه فرحتي.
The elders at home
كبار السن في المنزل
have consented to our marriage.
لقد وافقوا على زواجنا.
All auspicious signs have gathered.
لقد اجتمعت كل العلامات المبشرة.
Our two families rejoice.
عائلتانا تفرحان.
[Consort Virtue, Qi Rongyin]
[فضيلة القرين، تشي رونجين]
The six betrothal rites have been duly performed,
تم أداء طقوس الخطوبة الستة على النحو الواجب.
and all the ceremonial gifts are ready.
وجميع الهدايا الاحتفالية جاهزة.
Now, everything has been properly arranged.
الآن، تم ترتيب كل شيء بشكل صحيح.
Your company is all I need.
شركتكم هي كل ما أحتاجه.
I'll never betray you,
لن أخونك أبداً،
not until death do us part.
لن نفترق إلا بالموت.
To Yan, my dearest:
إلى يان، عزيزتي:
I hope you can feel my presence through these words.
أتمنى أن تشعروا بوجودي من خلال هذه الكلمات.
An imperial decree arrived suddenly,
صدر مرسوم إمبراطوري فجأة،
summoning me into the royal harem.
استدعوني إلى الحريم الملكي.
Bound by the Emperor's command,
ملتزمًا بأمر الإمبراطور،
I have no other choice.
ليس لدي خيار آخر.
As I savor the letters you wrote me,
بينما أستمتع بقراءة الرسائل التي كتبتها لي،
I feel deep affection.
أشعر بمودة عميقة.
Every word is engraved in my heart,
كل كلمة محفورة في قلبي،
as if it is whispered in my ear.
كما لو أنها تُهمس في أذني.
In the old days, you would pin flowers in my hair.
في الماضي، كنتِ تضعين الزهور في شعري.
The fragrance still lingers,
لا تزال الرائحة عالقة،
as if all that just happened yesterday.
وكأن كل ذلك حدث بالأمس.
The greatest regret in this world
أعظم ندم في هذا العالم
is for two people in love to be separated.
يعني ذلك أن يتم فصل شخصين متحابين.
From now on, I will be trapped in a golden cage,
من الآن فصاعدًا، سأكون محبوسًا في قفص ذهبي.
but my heart will roam with the clouds.
لكن قلبي سيظل يحلق مع الغيوم.
If you see a wild goose flying south,
إذا رأيت أوزة برية تحلق جنوباً،
consider it a loving message from me.
اعتبروها رسالة محبة مني.
From Rongyin,
من رونغين،
in tears before departure.
دموعها تنهمر قبل المغادرة.
[Li's Mansion]
[قصر لي]
Grandfather.
الجد.
Guards,
حراس،
take down my dear brother.
أسقط أخي العزيز.
What do you mean by this?
ماذا تقصد بهذا؟
You will understand
ستفهم
after the royal banquet.
بعد المأدبة الملكية.
So you've been feigning illness, Grandfather.
إذن كنت تتظاهر بالمرض يا جدي.
Wenkan,
شكرًا لك،
do you know how you failed?
هل تعرف كيف فشلت؟
He who is to achieve great things must be decisive
من أراد تحقيق إنجازات عظيمة عليه أن يكون حاسماً.
and remain composed when emotions are involved.
وأن يبقى هادئاً عندما يتعلق الأمر بالعواطف.
Your temperament determines
تحدد طبيعتك
that you will fail in every great undertaking.
أنك ستفشل في كل مشروع عظيم.
I act for the best of the family
أنا أتصرف بما يصب في مصلحة العائلة
and the country, while you for selfish gain.
والبلاد، بينما أنت تسعى لتحقيق مكاسب أنانية.
I'm not fated to become an unscrupulous man
ليس مقدراً لي أن أصبح رجلاً عديم الضمير
like you, Grandfather.
مثلك يا جدي.
You're such a fool!
يا لك من أحمق!
What has years of loyalty brought
ماذا جلبت سنوات من الولاء؟
us the Li family?
نحن عائلة لي؟
What have we gained in return?
ماذا ربحنا في المقابل؟
We have reached
لقد وصلنا
a point of no turning back.
نقطة اللاعودة.
We must ensure the Emperor's grandson ascends the throne.
يجب علينا ضمان أن يصعد حفيد الإمبراطور إلى العرش.
Even if he can't be a benevolent ruler,
حتى لو لم يستطع أن يكون حاكماً رحيماً،
we've embarked on a journey we can't turn back from.
لقد بدأنا رحلة لا يمكننا التراجع عنها.
Wenkan,
شكرًا لك،
there are thousands in our Li clan.
يوجد الآلاف في عشيرة لي الخاصة بنا.
You must stop confusing friends with foes
يجب عليك التوقف عن الخلط بين الأصدقاء والأعداء.
and siding with outsiders,
والانحياز إلى جانب الغرباء،
or the entire Li clan will be doomed,
وإلا فإن عشيرة لي بأكملها ستكون في خطر،
and the foundations of Great Yin will be shaken.
وستتزعزع أسس يين العظيم .
To the victor belongs the spoils— it's a rule since the ancient times.
الغنائم للفائز – إنها قاعدة منذ العصور القديمة.
One won't devote his life
لن يكرس المرء حياته
to his country unless personal interest is involved.
إلى بلاده ما لم تكن هناك مصلحة شخصية متضمنة.
Oh, you...
أوه، أنت...
All those studies
كل تلك الدراسات
have made you a stubborn fool.
لقد جعلك ذلك أحمق عنيداً.
The Eldest Young Master must not leave
لا يجوز للسيد الشاب الأكبر أن يغادر
the premises unless I order otherwise.
في المبنى ما لم آمر بخلاف ذلك.
-Yes!
- نعم!